Sylvester Rosa Koehler
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Correspondence, 1833-1904, undated, Series 1:; (Box 1-5; 5.0 linear feet)
  - Lorge, F. A., 1873-1889, (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 82-83)
  - Loring, Charles G., 1877-1889, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 84-87)
  - Low, Will H., 1881-1885 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - L, Miscellaneous: La-Lan, 1870-1890 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Labsap, [F.?]
    LaFarge, John
    Lamansky, S.
    Lamb, Charles R.
    Lambdin, Alfred
    Lambros, Spyr P.
    Landreth, Olin H.
    Lane, William C.
    Lange, Alvine (Mrs. J. D.)
    Langley, S. P.
    Lanman, Charles
    Lansil, Walter F.
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lau-Le, 1881-1888 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Lauber, Joseph
    Lawrence, Frank
    LeClear, Thomas
    Leaming, Thomas
    Lee, Jno. W. M.
    Leggo Bros. & Co.
    Lehuricht, Hermann
    Leibl, W.
    Leitz, Emil
    Lent, Frank T.
    Leveridge, C. A.
    Leypoldt, F.
  - L, Miscellaneous: Li, 1873-1896 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    L'Illustration
    Limpert, Ludwig
    Lindeman, Dr. Phil
    Linton, W. J.
    J. B. Lippincott & Co.
    Lippincott, William H.
    Lippmann, F.
    Littlefield, Mrs. S. E.
  - L, Miscellaneous: Lo-Ly, 1879-1886 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Longfellow, W. P. P.
    Lord, Grace V.
    Lorr, C.
    Lovejoy, Son & Co.
    Lovewell, R.
    Low, John G.
    Low, Lyman H.
    Lowell, William S.
    Lowenthal, E. J.
    Lutzow, Carl von
    Lyman, Jos., Jr.
  - MacAlister, James, 1879-1888 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Macleod, William, 1879-1885, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
  - Mansfield, John W., 1883-1885 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Martin, Henry A., 1877-1882 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Mason, Otis T., 1879-1881 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Mayer, Frank B., 1879-1886 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - McLaughlin, George, 1879-1886, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-17)
  - Meder, Ferdinand, 1888-1890 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Meehan, Thomas, 1878-1879, 1886-1887 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Merritt, Anna Lea, 1879-1881, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Meyer, Carl Herm, 1874-1879 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Middleton-Wake, Charles H., 1894-1895 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Miller, Charles Henry, 1880-1889 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Miller, William, 1880-1890, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 25-29)
  - Millet, F. D., 1880-1884 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Millet, J. B., 1881-1886 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mitchell, Francis B., 1883-1886 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Mitchell, J. A., 1880-1881 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Moran, Peter, 1879-1889 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Morse, Edward Sylvester, 1879-1889, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - Moses, H. H., 1873-1879, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Moss Engraving Co., 1880-1881, 1885, (5 folders) (Box 4, Folder 38-42)
  - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1880-1889 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - M, Miscellaneous: Ma-Mag, 1870-1885 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    MacDonald & Sons
    MacDonough, J.
    Macmillan & Co.
    Macomber, F. G.
    Maes, Camillus
    Magazine of Art
  - M, Miscellaneous: Man-Mat, 1877-1886 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Madel, P. H.
    Manhattan Photo-Engraving Company
    Marks, Montague
    Marquand, Allan
    Marshall, William E.
    Martin, Mary Bacon
    Mason, Charles J.
    Mason, George C.
    Mason, Perry
    Matchett, W. F.
    Mathews, Arthur F.
  - M, Miscellaneous: May, 1879-1883 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    Maycock, Mark M.
    Robert Mayer & Co.
    Maynard, George W.
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mc, 1867-1889 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    McCann, Hugh A.
    McCauley, C. A. H.
    McCoy, John W.
    McCutcheon, S. G.
    McDaniel, Elizabeth S. (Mrs. I. L.)
    McEntee, Jervis
    McLaughlin, Jas. W.
    McLaughlin, Mary Louise
    McLellan, Charles H.
  - M, Miscellaneous: Me-Mi, 1859, 1870-1889 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    Mechanical Company
    Meigs, Jabez B.
    Meissner & Buch
    Menger, Louis R.
    Meyer, Amandus
    Meyer, F.
    Meyer, Julius
    Michiels, Alfred
    Mitchell, Francis B.
    Miles, John C.
    Miller, France
    Miller, L. W.
    Miller, M.D.
    Miller, W. E.
    Millspaugh, J. H.
    Minot, Charles Sedwick
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mol-Moo, 1879-1885 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    Molleson Bros.
    Momgian, L.
    Momotaro Sato & Company
    Monks, J. A. S.
    Mooney, John
    Moor, Jacob B.
    Moore, Charles H.
    Moore, R. E.
  - M, Miscellaneous: Mor-Mu, 1876-1889 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    Moran, Mrs. M. Nimmo
    Moran, Paul
    Moran, Thomas
    Morse, Miss E. L.
    Mosler, Henry
    Moss, Frank
    Muller, Richard A.
    Munroe, Jas. V.
    Murphy, J. Francis
    Murray, David
    Murray, John
    Murrell, D. G.
  - Neal, David, 1881-1885 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Nicoll, J. C., 1880-1892, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 52-53)
  - Niemeyer, John H., 1880-1888 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1874-1889 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    Nashville Art Association
    Neely, J., Jr.
    Nelson, Anson
    Neuman & Hallman
    Newbury, Spencer
    Norcross, Laura
    Norton, C. B.
    Norton, C. E.
    Nutting, W. F.
  - Osborne, Charlotte, 1888-1890 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1871-1889 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    Oakey, Miss M. A.
    Orange Judd Company
    Orell Fussli & Co.
    Osborne, J. W.
    Osborne, Sidney
    Otis, A. B.
  - Palmer, George H., 1872-1873 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Parrish, Stephen, 1880-1889, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 59-61)
  - Pearce, Charles Sprague, 1880-1881, 1887 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Perkins, Charles C., 1871-1896, undated, (10 folders) (Box 4, Folder 63-72)
  - Photo-Electrotype Co., 1880-1881, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Photo-Engraving Co., 1879-1881, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 74-75)
  - Photo-Gravure Company, 1885-1888 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Pickering, Edward C., 1875-1878 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Pinches, Thoe. G., 1879-1880 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Platt, Charles A., 1881, 1885 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Prang, Louis (L. Prang and Co.), 1868-1889 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Pratt, Waldo S., 1880-1881, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 81-82)
  - Preston, Margaret J. (Mrs. J. T. L. Preston), 1879-1882 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Prime, William C., 1879-1881 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Putnam, Frederic W., 1879-1881 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pa, 1880-1889 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    Paar, Hermann
    Palmer, Alice W.
    Palmer, J. E., Jr.
    Palmer, Walter L.
    Paris, Walter
    Park, John G.
    Parton, Arthur
    Pascoe, Charles E.
    Paul, C. Kegan
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pe, 1865-1888 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    Peabody & Stearns
    Peckham, Rosa F.
    Peet, Stephen D.
    Peirce, Edith L.
    Penfold, F. C.
    Perkins, Edward
    Perry, Winthrop H.
    Peschan, F. W. E.
    Petromann, Theodor
  - P, Miscellaneous: Ph-Pi, 1879-1887 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    Philadelphia Centennial Exposition
    Phillips, Barnet
    Phillips, Henry, Jr.
    Phillips, J. W., Jr.
    Phinney, Emma E.
    Pierce, Charles F.
    Pierce, S. E.
    Pierson, postmaster
    P[iph?], H.
    Pitman, Benn
  - P, Miscellaneous: Po, 1870-1887 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    Poillon, Wm.
    Pollock, Charles
    Poore, Harry R.
    Porter, George M.
    Powell, J. W.
    Powers & Weightman
  - P, Miscellaneous: Pr-Pu, 1872-1890 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    Preston, John Aiken
    Prud'homme, John F. E.
    Publishers' Weekly
    Putnam, G. P.
  - Quantin, A., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Riordan, Roger, 1880-1888, (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 92-94)
  - Rotch, Arthur, 1880-1883 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Rowlands, Walter, 1877-1890, (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 96-97)
  - R, Miscellaneous: Ra-Rie, 1869-1889 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    Ramsdell, H. Powell
    Rand, George D.
    Randebruch, J. F.
    Rattermann, H. A.
    Redaction Der Illustrirten Zeitung in Leipzig
    Reddon-Learing, Laura
    Reed, Thomas R.
    Reinhart, Charles S.
    Rewling, Dr. G.
    Rice, Richard A.
    Richards, T. Addison
    Richards, William V.
    Richardson, F. H.
    Richardson, Thomas O.
    Riedler, Maxim
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rim-Rob, 1873-1888 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    Rimmer, Caroline Hunt
    Riotte, C. N.
    Ritchie, G. W. H.
    Robbins, E. O.
    Robert, Mrs. A. J.
    Robinson, Charles
    Robinson, Frank T.
    Robinson, Henry H.
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rog-Ros, 1872-1900 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    Rogers, Fairman
    Rondot, Natalie
    Ropp, Alfred
    Rosenberg, Adolf
    Ross, Jno. Joline
  - R, Miscellaneous: Rou-Ry, 1879-1890 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    Rouam, J.
    Round, W. M. F.
    Ruster, H. H.
    Russell, C. H., Jr.
    Russell, F. P.
    Russell, Samuel H.
    Russell & Richardson
    Ryan, John T.
  - Savage, A. Duncan, 1879-1885, (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 102-105)
  - Schem, A. J., 1872-1878 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Schoenhof, Carl, 1881-1889 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Schoff, Stephen A., 1878-1889, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 3-8)
  - Schunemann-Poss, Freidrich, 1867-1874 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Schweinfurth, Julius A., 1879-1880 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Scribner and Co. (Charles Scribner's Sons), 1878-1880 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Seeman, E. A., 1879-1880, 1890, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 12-14)
  - Sewall, Henry F., 1885-1889 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Shirlaw, Walter, 1881-1886 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Smillie, James D., 1879-1890, 1895, (11 folders) (Box 5, Folder 17-27)
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1881-1890 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Spaulding, Henry G., 1876-1880 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Sprague, Julia A., 1886-1890, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Stetson, Charles Walter, 1882-1885 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Sturgis, Russell, 1879-1880, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
  - Swett, Susan, 1880-1881 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sa, 1877-1890 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Sabin, J. F.
    Sachtleben, A.
    Saffield, Thomas
    Sampson, Alden
    Sandham, Henry
    Sargent, C. S.
    Sartain, Emily
    Sartain, John
    Saunders, Frederick
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sc-Sch, 1870-1891 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Scribner & Welford
    Schell, Fred B.
    Schilling, Alex
    Schlosser, H.
    Schmidt, Delius
    Schraubstadter, Carl, Jr.
    Schreiber, W. L.
    Schultz, H. E.
    Schulze, Paul
    Schumm, George
    Schuricht, Herrmann
    Schuster, Rudolph
    Schwarz, L.
    Schwazenbach, Jos.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Scu-Sel, 1880-1890 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Scudder, Miss
    Sears, George Edward
    Sears, J. M.
    Sedelmeyer, Charles
    Seitz, Emil
    Selinger, John
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sen-Sha, 1871-1889 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Senat, Prosper L.
    Sentz, Theodor
    P. M. Shanks & Co.
    Share, H. P.
    Sharp, John S.
    Sharp, William
    Shaw, Annie C.
    Shaw, C. H.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Shi-Sl, 1870-1882 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Shinn, Earl
    Shuman, Roger M.
    Shoninger, Jos.
    Sigmund, J. C.
    Sihler, K. Elizabeth
    Silliman, B.
    Skeel, Lucy
    Slack, Charles W.
    Sloan, Charles F.
  - S, Miscellaneous: Sm, 1879-1887 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Smart, W. G. H.
    Smillie, George H.
    Smith, Benj. E.
    Smith, Frank Hill
    Smith, Marshall J., Jr.
    Smith, Mary Stuart
    Smith, Thomas C.
    Smith, Walter
    Smithson, T. W.
    Smithwick, John G.
  - S, Miscellaneous: So-Sp, 1877-1886 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Solberg, Thorvald
    Somerville, James M.
    Spemann, W.
    Spencer, H. L.
  - S, Miscellaneous: St-Su, 1872-1889 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Stanton, J. M.
    Stanwood, Edward
    Steiger, E.
    Stevens, Samuel
    Stone, F. D.
    Stornay, J. O.
    Stuart, Jas. R.
    Sturgis, John H.
    Sutro, Emil
    Sutton, James
  - Tait, John Robinson, 1879-1887, (5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 43-47)
  - Terquem, Emil, 1879-1883 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Tileston and Hollingsworth, 1879-1881 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Tracy, John M., 1870, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ta-Th, 1884-1889 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Tallmadege, Frederick S.
    Taphy, W. A.
    Teel, George A.
    Temple, F. L.
    Teubner, H.
    Thayer, Abbott H.
  - T, Miscellaneous: Ti-To, 1871-1886 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Tietze, R. G.
    Tilden, Geroge T.
    Tillinghast, C. B.
    Tobey, S. E.
    Tombola
    Townley, D.
  - T, Miscellaneous: Tr-Ty, 1870-1890 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    Trafton, Edwin H.
    Trinity Historical Society
    Trotter, Newbold H.
    Trouvelot, George
    True, F. W.
    Trumble, Alfred
    Tuckerman, H. T.
    Turner, C. Y.
    Turnure, Arthur B.
    Tyndale, T. H.
  - Unger, William, 1879-1880 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - U, Miscellaneous, 1870-1886 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    Ulrich, Charles F.
    United States Centennial Commission
    United States Treasurey Department
  - Van Brunt, Henry, 1879-1880 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Van Elten, Kruseman, 1880-1887 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Van Rensselaer, Mariana G., 1879-1889, (9 folders) (Box 5, Folder 58-66)
  - Vinton, Frederic P., 1879-1892, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 67-68)
  - Volkmer, Charles, 1880-1883 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Von Lutzow, Carl, 1869-1890 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - V, Miscellaneous: V-Va, 1859, 1877-1885 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    D. V. [initials only]
    Valentine, Edward V.
    Van Cleef, Aug.
    Vanderhoof, Charles A.
    Van Nostrand, D.
    Van Rensselaer, Schuyler
    Vaux, Calvert
  - V, Miscellaneous: Ve-Vol, 1878-1888 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    Verestchagin, Vassili
    Vignal, E.
    Vogel, Hermann
    Volkmann, Meta
  - V, Miscellaneous: Von-Voy, 1879-1886 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    Von Hillern, Bertha
    Von Hoesslin, George
    Von Tschudi, Hugo
    Von Waldheim, R.
    Vorholz, A.
    Voynl, L.
  - Ware, William Rotch, 1875-1888, undated, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 74-75)
  - Wells, Kate Gannett, 1881, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Wellstood, William, 1879-1880, (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 77-79)
  - Wendt, Mathilde F., 1870-1881 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Wheeler, Dora, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Whipple, H. C., 1877, 1885-1890 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Whitney, Elias J., 1880-1881, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Wight, P. B., 1879-1880, 1882, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 84-85)
  - Wilson, John, 1879-1886 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Winthrop, T. L., 1880-1881 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wa-Wal, 1870-1887 (Box 5, Folder 88)
    Wagner, H. Dumont
    Wager-Fisher, Mary
    Waldheim, H.
    Walker, Charles A.
    Walker, Howard
    Wall, Mary Minton
    Wallace, W. Henry
    Waller, Frank
    Wallis, George
    Walter, James
    Walther, August
  - W, Miscellaneous: War-Wel, 1873-1889 (Box 5, Folder 89)
    Ward, Edgar M.
    Ward, Ella F.
    Ward, J. Humphrey
    Warder, R. H.
    Waterston, R. C.
    Watkins, J. Elfreth
    Wehle, Charles
    Weigel, T. O.
    Weir, John F.
    Welch, Joseph
    Welch, Bigelow, and Company
    Wells, Charles L.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wes-Whe, 1871-1886 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    Wesselhoft, William P.
    West, Charles E.
    Westcott, Thompson
    B. Westerman & Co.
    Weyprecht, Louis J.
    Wheeler, Candace
    Wheeler, Dunham
    Wheeler, William A.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Whi-Who, 1879-1889, undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
    White, George Merwanjee
    Whitehouse, F. C.
    Whitman, E. F.
    Whitmore, W. H.
    W[holst?], W.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wi-Wilm, 1870-1887 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    Wibiral, F.
    Wickersham, Morris S.
    Wiese, F.
    Wigand, Otto C.
    Wight, William W.
    Wiles, L. M.
    Williams, George P.
    Williams, Ichabod T.
    Wilmurt, Thomas A.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wils-Wis, 1879-1889 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    Wilson, Anna M.
    Wilson, Edward S.
    Wilson, George
    Wilson, Solon D.
    Winslow, W. Henry
    Wiseman, Robert R.
  - W, Miscellaneous: Wo-Wy, 1879-1889 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    Wolf, Henry
    Wood, T. W.
    Woodward, Wilbur W.
    Worsnop, C. Arthur
    Wright, George
    Wright, Margaret Bertha
    H. Wunderlich & Co.
    Wyatt, J. Noel
  - Y, Miscellaneous, 1879-1886 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    Yale, Leroy M.
    Young, Charles L., Jr.
    Young, Jennie L.
  - Unidentifiable and Illegible, 1858, 1870-1890, undated, (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 96-101)
- Financial Records, 1870-1890, undated, Series 2:; (Box 6; 14 folders)
  Financial Records include Koehler's receipts, mostly dating 1885. The receipts are primarily for the purchase of books, but are also for professional services, printing, advertising, and membership dues. Also found is a handwritten estimate of costs for publishing the American Art Review.
  - Cost estimate for publishing American Art Review, circa 1879 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1870-1890, undated, (13 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 2-14)
- Miscellany, 1859-1896, undated, Series 3:; (Box 6; 10 folders)
  This series includes a folder of biographical information on the wood engraver, Alexander Anderson. Also found are various notes and quotations by unidentified authors many of which are written on small envelopes. Also included are event programs and handwritten song texts for music performances. This series also contains news clippings. Most of the material in this series is in German.
  - Biographical Information on Alexander Anderson, 1886 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 15)
  - Calling Cards and Address Notes, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 16)
  - Envelopes with Notes and Quotations, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 17)
  - Event Programs, 1862-1864 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 18)
  - Handwritten Song Texts, 1859, undated, (4 folders) (Box 6 (hol), Folder 19-22)
  - News Clippings, 1867-1868, 1896 (Box 6 (hol), Folder 23)
  - Notes by Unidentified Authors, undated (Box 6 (hol), Folder 24)